CURRICULUM VITAE

JAEYONG LEE

South Korean (30) based on Helsinki, Finland

Mobile: +358 (0)46 577 5140 Email: jaeyonglee05@gmail.com Portfolio: www.studiojaeyonglee.com

LinkedIn: https://fi.linkedin.com/in/jaeyonglee05

PROFILE

I am a UX/Visual designer who endeavors to bring positive changes in people's lives by transforming complex design issues into persuasive, experiential and effective design solutions. My design capabilities include UX and service design: creating UX strategy, information architecture, UI design, user flow map, interactive prototype as well as investigating the needs of users and analyzing it. I am confident at conducting UX projects starting from user researches to the implementable design guidelines through various design methodologies: Human-Centered Design, Co-Design, Lean and Agile UX.

EXPERIENCE

Master thesis Student Philips, NL

Jan.2016~Nov.2016

- Proposed new UI designs and design guidelines for *Philips Smart Air Purifier*: a data measuring device for real-time air quality and its mobile app.
- Conducted empirical user researches in the context of air quality and investigated the interconnections between visual perception and behavior change.

Design Intern

Philips, SG Sep. 2015~Nov .2015

- Created information & data visualization for *Primary Care project* in healthcare business.
- Developed UI design for Philips Online Shop Singapore website.

Visual designer *0100design, KR* Jan. 2012-Apr .2014

- In charge of creating various visual designs for brands, products and interiors.
- Created visual identity of *0100design*: website, logo, visual concepts.
- Developed visual concepts of interior and furniture designs for the *Chonbuk National University library*.
- Designed trophies for the Expo 2012 Yeosu Korea.

Co-founder & Visual designer

Keida studio, KR Jan.2011~Dec.2011

- Conducted various artistic experiments, design campaigns for social issues, conceptual product designs
- Awarded Red Dot Concept Design Award 2012 through 'Traveler's Paper Kit'.

Product design intern

FS Korea LTD, KR Jan.2011~Mar.2011 • Designed cosmetic containers and conducted market researches

Visual designer

Floating Island, KR Jan.2009~Aug.2009

- Created visual design concepts for animations: White Ball and Let's go MBA
- Directed 2 short animation films: *Shadow*, *My friend Muchi*, as independent projects

EDUCATION

Collaborative and Industrial Design

Aalto University, FI Master of Arts Aug. 2014~Present

- Cumulative GPA: 4.25/5 scale
- Specialization in UI/UX design, service design and user research through user-centered approaches.
- Conducted various collaborative projects with companies and public organizations: City of Helsinki, the Finnish Tax administration, Aalto University, Kemppi and Philips.

Visual Communication Design, Metal Craft

Hongik University, KR Bachelor of Arts Mar. 2005~Feb. 2012

- Cumulative GPA: 4.04 / 4.5 scale; Merit-based Scholarship Recipient five times.
- Conducted projects for graphic design, illustration, animation and craft.
- Served *military service* between Jul. 2006 and Jul. 2008 in South Korea ROK army headquarters.

HONOR & AWARD

Full scholarship student • NIIFD

Aug. 2014

Selected as a representative scholarship student by *National Institute for International Education (NIIED)* and fully supported for master's study for 2 years.

3rd prize

LOTTE World Tower Mall Apr. 2014 Winning work: Lopy, Mascot design of Lotte World Tower Mall and relevant applications design

Honorable Mention

Red Dot Design Award Sep. 2013 Winning work: *Life-Light*, emergency directional system for evacuation

Winner

Red Dot Design Award Sep. 2012 Winning work: Traveler's Paper Kit, emergency paper kit for travelers

Good Design Selection *Korea Good Design*

Aug. 2012

 Winning work: Triangle Gate, optical electronic gate indicating clear direction

Encouragement prize

Junk Art Contest Nov. 2011 Winning work: Spectacle #1, Junk Art using abandoned electronic devices and video art

Excellence Award

Cartoon Contest Sep. 2008 • Winning work: *Too dangerous to touch*, a story about dangerousness of having drugs

SKILLS

Excellent

 Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, InVision, After Effects, Premiere Pro, Audition, InDesign, Muse

Moderate

• MS Office, 3D Max, Maya, CAD, HTML, CSS

LANGUAGE

Mother tongue Fluent

Basic

KoreanEnglish

Japanese

JAEYONG LEE

South Korean (30) based in Helsinki, Finland

Mobile: +358 (0)46 577 5140 Email: jaeyonglee05@gmail.com Portfolio: www.studiojaeyonglee.com

LinkedIn: https://fi.linkedin.com/in/jaeyonglee05